<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Idea Switching</title>
    <description>Networking, Security, Automation &amp; Development</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 15:16:26 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 15:16:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Not perfect, but works at least</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A Solutions Architect needs to use AWS to implement pilot light disaster recovery for a three-tier web application hosted in an on-premises datacenter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which solution allows rapid provision of working, fully-scaled production environment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continuously replicate the production database server to Amazon RDS. Use AWS CloudFormation to deploy the application and any additional servers if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continuously replicate the production database server to Amazon RDS. Create one application load balancer and register on-premises servers. Configure ELB Application Load Balancer to automatically deploy Amazon EC2 instances for application and additional servers if the on-premises application is down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a scheduled Lambda function to replicate the production database to AWS. Use Amazon Route 53 health checks to deploy the application automatically to Amazon S3 if production is unhealthy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a scheduled Lambda function to replicate the production database to AWS. Register on-premises servers to an Auto Scaling group and deploy the application and additional servers if production is unavailable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iteablue.com/forums/topic/%e8%bf%99%e9%81%93%e9%a2%98%e6%b1%82%e8%a7%a3&quot;&gt;这道题提问的人选择了3&lt;/a&gt;，而博主给出的参考答案是2。我的看法则是1，原因如下：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3和4中的明显问题是用Lambda定期复制数据库到AWS。同时4中提到把本地服务器注册到ASG是无法完成的；&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1和2两个答案中，1实现了复制生产环境的基本需求。2相对来说更加完善，但是“Configure ELB Application Load Balancer to automatically deploy Amazon EC2 instances”是ELB不支持的。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;所以综合来看，1虽然相对不完美，但是没有其他错误。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/Q59-SAA</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Q59-SAA</guid>
        
        <category>AWS</category>
        
        <category>ELB</category>
        
        <category>EC2</category>
        
        <category>Lambda</category>
        
        
        <category>Try To Elaborate - AWS</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Amazon Solutions Architect - Professional 认证心得</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;在经过几个月的准备之后，终于在10月4号第二次尝试中通过SAP考试。
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/rJz01OX.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2019-10-05 at 11.20.36&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/N7hkr5Q.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Shot 2019-10-05 at 11.20.48&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;以下是我对SAP考试的一些心得。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;注意官方手册，文档和资料。官方的文档中包含了很多非常有用的信息，但是这些点会比较分散。同时官方的手册中包含了很多考试的题目和答案（基本是稍微总结的水平），大量阅读官方手册，记录官方文档中对技术的选择可以让考试轻松很多。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;注意自己总结知识点。正如上面所说的，官方文档为了保持单篇文档的可读性，对每篇文档的前后信息都有足够的铺垫。但是在SAP考试的准备中，这些前后铺垫会浪费大量的时间，所以应该自己对文档中提到的知识点来进行总结。比如Kinesis的最长保持时间，我也是在文档中某一句话中看到的。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;不要错在送分题。任何厂商认证都有宣传自己产品的目的，那么解决方案会尽量以推广自己产品为主。如果看到非亚马逊的解决方案，虽然不一定是错的，但是最好有足够的理由之后再选择。同事AWS主要是帮助企业把自身服务往云服务迁移，那么多用对应的组件才是更合理的选择（但不绝对）。比如No-SQL一般不该考虑用Aurora来替代。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;题目太长，不用全读。不管英语是否足够熟练，我认为都不用每道题都完整的读题。这样不仅浪费时间，而且过多的信息反而会影响判断。多注意看关键词，同时多注意看题目中背景信息。比如说问题出在网页服务的网络上，那就不太应该去考虑如何提升数据库的性能。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;确认考场。AWS认证现在可以通过Pearson和PSI两个机构进行考试。考前最好了解一下考场的情况。对于环境太差的考场要一定慎重选择。其次，有其他的考友反馈PSI考场不允许中途离场，对于这样的考场要同样慎重选择，毕竟190分钟的考试是很漫长的。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;如果没过，注意调整心态。如果如此不幸，调整心态再来一次就好。亚马逊的考试总的来说还是比较直观的，在知识点准备充足的情况下，大部分题目可以很快排除掉许多答案。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/SAP%E8%80%83%E8%AF%95%E8%AE%A4%E8%AF%81%E5%BF%83%E5%BE%97</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/SAP%E8%80%83%E8%AF%95%E8%AE%A4%E8%AF%81%E5%BF%83%E5%BE%97</guid>
        
        <category>AWS</category>
        
        <category>Certificate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Miss a step, miss the whole</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A company has developed a new billing application that will be released in two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers are testing the application running on 10 EC2 instances managed by an Auto Scaling group in subnet 172.31.0.0/24 within VPC A with CIDR block 172.31.0.0/16. The Developers noticed connection timeout errors in the application logs while connecting to an Oracle database running on an Amazon EC2 instance in the same region within VPC B with CIDR block 172.50.0.0/16. The IP of the database instance is hard- coded in the application instances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which recommendations should a Solutions Architect present to the Developers to solve the problem in a secure way with minimal maintenance and overhead?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disable the SrcDestCheck attribute for all instances running the application and Oracle Database. Change the default route of VPC A to point ENI of the Oracle Database that has an IP address assigned within the range of 172.50.0.0/26&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create and attach internet gateways for both VPCs. Configure default routes to the Internet gateways for both VPCs. Assign an Elastic IP for each Amazon EC2 instance in VPC A&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a VPC peering connection between the two VPCs and add a route to the routing table of VPC A that points to the IP address range of 172.50.0.0/16&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create an additional Amazon EC2 instance for each VPC as a customer gateway; create one virtual private gateway (VGW) for each VPC, configure an end-to-end VPC, and advertise the routes for 172.50.0.0/16&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;这道题看似非常的简单，但是却非常容易出错。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;要使两个VPC能够通信，&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/vpc/latest/peering/peering-configurations-full-access.html&quot;&gt;文档&lt;/a&gt;里有清楚的方法。很明显，答案3符合完全按照手册中的方法来配置，&lt;strong&gt;唯独少在VPC B中配置路由这一步&lt;/strong&gt;。我们不要认为答案有错或者有黑科技可以省去一步。&lt;strong&gt;如果答案不符合官方文档，我们可以直接认为它不是合理的答案。&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;其实答案4也是一个可以满足题目需求的答案，但这个方法并不是文档中直接提到的，而是需要组合自己的知识来得到的。其实现的最后结果，就像是自己在两个VPC之间手动做起了peering。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/Q5</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Q5</guid>
        
        <category>AWS</category>
        
        <category>VPC</category>
        
        <category>VGW</category>
        
        
        <category>Try To Elaborate - AWS</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Choose the best when there are options</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A company collects a steady stream of 10 million data records from 100,000 sources each day. These records are written to an Amazon RDS MySQL DB. A query must produce the daily average of a data source over the past 30 days. There are twice as many reads as writes. Queries to the collected data are for one source ID at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can the Solutions Architect improve the reliability and cost effectiveness of this solution?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Amazon Aurora with MySQL in a Multi-AZ mode. Use four additional read replicas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Amazon DynamoDB with the source ID as the partition key and the timestamp as the sort key. Use a Time to Live (TTL) to delete data after 30 days.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Amazon DynamoDB with the source ID as the partition key. Use a different table each day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ingest data into Amazon Kinesis using a retention period of 30 days. Use AWS Lambda to write data records to Amazon ElastiCache for read access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;答案中比较明显的是B、C采用了DynamoDB，而题目中说明使用了MySQL。采用这两种方案需要对数据库进行非常大的改动。一般来说这种方案除非有深思熟虑，在实际情况中是不会采纳的。所以这里可以比较容易的排除B、C两项。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;答案A和D中，乍一看都是可以满足所有需求：一定量的数据写入，两倍于写入的读取需求性能和查询最近30天的平均值。但答案A相比D更加合理：&lt;/del&gt;
&lt;del&gt;* 数据并没有说明只保留30天，答案A可以长期保留数据。而D在30天之后数据即消失&lt;/del&gt;
&lt;del&gt;* Kinesis更加强调实时性，这里并没有提出这种需求&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;综合来看，A是最佳的答案。&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;经过其他群友的提醒，&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/streams/latest/dev/kinesis-extended-retention.html&quot;&gt;文档中&lt;/a&gt;明确了Kinesis里数据最长保存时间是7天（168小时），所以答案4也是不正确的。所以只能选答案1。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/Q4</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Q4</guid>
        
        <category>AWS</category>
        
        <category>Kinesis</category>
        
        <category>Database</category>
        
        <category>Aurora</category>
        
        
        <category>Try To Elaborate - AWS</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>People should pay for what they use</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A group of research institutions and hospitals are in a partnership to study 2 PBs of genomic data. The institute that owns the data stores it in an Amazon S3 bucket and updates it regularly. The institute would like to give all of the organizations in the partnership read access to the data. All members of the partnership are extremely cost-conscious, and the institute that owns the account with the S3 bucket is concerned about covering the costs for requests and data transfers from Amazon S3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which solution allows for secure data-sharing without causing the institute that owns the bucket to assume all the costs for S3 requests and data transfers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ensure that all organizations in the partnership have AWS accounts. In the account with the S3 bucket, create a cross-account role for each account in the partnership that allows read access to the data. Have the organizations assume and use that read role when accessing the data.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ensure that all organizations in the partnership have AWS accounts. Create a bucket policy on the bucket that owns the data. The policy should allow the accounts in the partnership read access to the bucket. Enable Requester Pays on the bucket. Have the organizations use their AWS credentials when accessing the data.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ensure that all organizations in the partnership have AWS accounts. Configure buckets in each of the accounts with a bucket policy that allows the institute that owns the data the ability to write to the bucket. Periodically sync the data from the institute’s account to the other organizations. Have the organizations use their AWS credentials when accessing the data using their accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ensure that all organizations in the partnership have AWS accounts. In the account with the S3 bucket, create a cross-account role for each account in the partnership that allows read access to the data. Enable Requester Pays on the bucket. Have the organizations assume and use that read role when accessing the data.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;问题中说到了共享数据的时候，不希望对数据拥有者造成请求和数据传输上的费用。那么这就表明了需要请求者来支付相应的费用。从答案来看，2和4的Enable Requester Pays满足条件。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;但问题的难点即在这里，2和4两个答案都提出了这样的解决方案：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;所有的机构都有自己AWS账号&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;允许其他机构对数据进行访问&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;启用请求者支付&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;用自己的账号访问数据&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;这里最大的区别是在如何共享S3数据的方式上。2和4采用的方法都可以完成数据的共享，其方法分别是&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/premiumsupport/knowledge-center/cross-account-access-s3/&quot;&gt;文档&lt;/a&gt;中Resource-based Access和Cross-account IAM roles两种方式。但如果结合&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/RequesterPaysBuckets.html&quot;&gt;Requester Pays Buckets文档&lt;/a&gt;中的这句话&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When the requester assumes an AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) role prior to making their request, the account to which the role belongs is charged for the request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;来看，role所在的account会被用来支付费用。所以答案4中的共享方式，其他组织通过cross-account role来访问数据，由于这些role都是数据拥有者账号内创建的， 所以实际的费用支付者还是数据拥有者。这样就并不能实际达到Requester Pays的效果。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;所以最后答案选2。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/Q3</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Q3</guid>
        
        <category>AWS</category>
        
        <category>S3</category>
        
        <category>bucket policy</category>
        
        <category>cross account</category>
        
        
        <category>Try To Elaborate - AWS</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NGW &amp; IGW</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Application servers currently deployed in a private subnet require the ability to integrate with a third-party service accessible through the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which changes are required to provide outbound Internet connectivity in the VPC without providing inbound Internet connectivity to the application servers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a NAT Gateway without attaching an Internet Gateway to the VPC.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a NAT Gateway and attach an Internet Gateway to the VPC.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attach an Internet Gateway to the VPC without creating a NAT Gateway.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attach a Virtual Private Gateway to the VPC and create a NAT Gateway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;问题中明确了：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;能够通过访问互联网&lt;/strong&gt;。这一点应该是暗示Internet Gateway。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/vpc/latest/userguide/VPC_Internet_Gateway.html&quot;&gt;that allows communication between instances in your VPC and the internet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;但是并不需要互联网能够回访&lt;/strong&gt;。这一点应该是暗示NAT Gateway。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/vpc/latest/userguide/vpc-nat-gateway.html&quot;&gt;enable instances in a private subnet to connect to the internet or other AWS services, but prevent the internet from initiating a connection with those instances.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;对于两种网关，NAT Gateway中的图示很有参考价值，表明了两者的职责和区别。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The following diagram illustrates the architecture of a VPC with a NAT gateway. The main route table sends internet traffic from the instances in the private subnet to the NAT gateway. The NAT gateway sends the traffic to the internet gateway using the NAT gateway’s Elastic IP address as the source IP address.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/7COfpVf.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;而第4个答案中的Virtual Private Gate是Site-to-Site VPN的终结点。可以很容易排除。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/Q2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Q2</guid>
        
        <category>AWS</category>
        
        <category>NAT Gateway</category>
        
        <category>Internet Gateway</category>
        
        <category>Virtual Private Gateway</category>
        
        
        <category>Try To Elaborate - AWS</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Try to Elaborate 简介</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;那些声称清楚自己所想，但却不能清晰表达的人，其实通常不知道自己所想。— Mortimer Adler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;经常在学习的过程中，自己和群友都会遇到或多或少类似的问题。比如技术之间的区别、练习题种的疑惑，以及方案之间的差别。虽然网络上对于很多信息都有官方的文档，但在这些之外的解释却是非常稀缺。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;著名的费曼学习方法中的第一步便是用自己的语言解释自己所学的东西，而不是生搬硬套原本的文字。所以在自己的学习过程中，便想直接记录下学习过程中的一些心得。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;这个系列算是学习笔记，计划从练习题的解答开始。个人水平有限，如有错误，还望指正。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;本系列的所有练习题均是通过正规在线学习网站（Linux Academy等）获得，本人没有题库资料&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/Try-to-Elaborate-AWS</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Try-to-Elaborate-AWS</guid>
        
        <category>AWS</category>
        
        
        <category>Try To Elaborate - AWS</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scale Your Services with Load Balancers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A load balancer (LB) is a device that acts as a reverse proxy and distributes network or application traffic across a number of servers. LBs are used to increase capacity (concurrent users) and reliability of applications. They improve the overall performance of applications by decreasing the burden on servers associated with managing and maintaining application and network sessions, as well as by performing application-specific tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of Load Balancers will be mentioned in this article, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;general Layer 7 (application) layer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DNS L7 layer load balancers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;L4 (transport) layer load balancers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;general L3 (network)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anycast load balancers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll ignore most of the jargons to minimize preceded knowledge of computer networking, except the basic idea of OSI 7 layer model. The OSI 7 layer model is a model used to separate responsibilities of devices in a network, providing transparent and standard interfaces to both upper and lower layers. They’re named from high to low as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application Layer (Layer 7). High-level APIs, including resource sharing, remote file access&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Presentation Layer. Translation of data between a networking service and an application; including character encoding, data compression, and encryption/decryption&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Session Layer. Managing communication sessions, i.e. continuous exchange of information in the form of multiple back-and-forth transmissions between two nodes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transport Layer. Reliable transmission of data segments between points on a network, including segmentation, and multiplexing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Network Layer. Structuring and managing a multi-node network, including addressing, routing and traffic control&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Link Layer. Reliable transmission of data frames between two nodes connected by a physical layer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Physical Layer (Layer 1). Transmission and reception of raw bit stream over a physical medium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any layer of them, its upper layer and lower are transparent if available, meaning it isn’t capable of having any insight of other layers. This is a very important concept for OSI model and will be implied in the following article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;types-of-lbs&quot;&gt;Types of LBs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;l7-application-layer&quot;&gt;L7, application layer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An L7 load balancer operates at the highest level of OSI level, but this doesn’t mean it has insights for all layers, but simply L7. The content in L7  is the actual information of applications, which includes HTTP, DNS, and FTP etc. This gives the L7 LB ability to terminate traffic and make decisions based on the content of messages, such as URL and cookie. It then forwards traffic to actual servers behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dns&quot;&gt;DNS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DNS is an L7 protocol mentioned previously, so a DNS LB should operate as same as a general L7 LB, right? Applications usually query DNS to find the IP address of a domain, they will then follow the response to reach the destination. A DNS LB is not an LBed DNS group, is a (set of) DNS server(s)  returning a set of pre-defined DNS records, which changes itself each query, typically by with the round-robin method.  Since the response changes every time w/o considering caching, applications are distributed to a group of servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;l4-tcpudp-lb&quot;&gt;L4, TCP/UDP LB&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An L4 load balancer comes into consideration when there is more traffic. It includes TCP and UDP. The L4 load balancer simply forwards packets by using their pairs of IP address and port number or port numbers alone. It allows load balance specific flows across pools. As mentioned above, it has no ability to inspect any content that is higher than L4, meaning it can’t make routing decisions based on the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;l3-network-layer&quot;&gt;L3, network layer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Layer 3 load balancers are typically based on the IP protocol. It sees only IP information usually and makes a decision solely on IP address (source and/or destination).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anycast&quot;&gt;Anycast&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the internet use unicast. It means routing devices find best (usually shortest) path to a destination (IP). Anycast is a technique that multiple network devices share the same IP address. The routers will consider them as the same destination with different path costs and will choose the best one by their policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;common-algorithms-and-related-techniques&quot;&gt;Common algorithms and related techniques&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;round-robin-rr&quot;&gt;Round Robin (RR)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the simplest algorithm used in LB. Imagining a set of server returns one answer with instances A, B, and C behind, the answers will follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A -&amp;gt; B -&amp;gt; C -&amp;gt; A -&amp;gt; B -&amp;gt; C -&amp;gt; A -&amp;gt; …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;weighted-round-robin-wrr&quot;&gt;Weighted Round Robin (WRR)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RR is robust because of its simplicity. If we have a set of servers with different performance, and we want to distribute traffic fairly not equally, the WRR fits perfectly. This method operates the same way as RR, but a server with a higher weight will receive more traffic in a round. Taking the same example except server B weighing 2, its response will follow or similar:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A -&amp;gt; B -&amp;gt; B -&amp;gt; C -&amp;gt; A -&amp;gt; B -&amp;gt; B -&amp;gt; C -&amp;gt; A -&amp;gt; …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;state-tracking&quot;&gt;State tracking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If an LB is capable of tracking states of traffic, there are more possible algorithms used to make decisions. Methods, such as least connection and least response time, need to track states of connections, they may provide some benefits in some cases but will become a bottleneck when traffic goes larger and larger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;health-check&quot;&gt;Health check&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Health checking is almost a requirement for using LB, though it isn’t mandatory. The health checking works as its name suggests: regularly check a service is still live to determine whether following traffic to be re-directed to this service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/Scale-Your-Services-with-Load-Balancers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/Scale-Your-Services-with-Load-Balancers</guid>
        
        <category>Network</category>
        
        <category>Load Balance</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Next Theme Tutorial</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;NexT is a high quality elegant &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; theme ported from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/iissnan/hexo-theme-next&quot;&gt;Hexo Next&lt;/a&gt;. It is crafted from scratch, with love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://simpleyyt.github.io/jekyll-theme-next/&quot;&gt;Live Preview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;screenshots&quot;&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Desktop
&lt;img src=&quot;http://iissnan.com/nexus/next/desktop-preview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Desktop Preview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sidebar&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://iissnan.com/nexus/next/desktop-sidebar-preview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Desktop Sidebar Preview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sidebar (Post details page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://iissnan.com/nexus/next/desktop-sidebar-toc.png&quot; alt=&quot;Desktop Sidebar Preview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mobile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://iissnan.com/nexus/next/mobile.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mobile Preview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check whether you have &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ruby 2.1.0&lt;/code&gt; or higher installed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ruby &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--version&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bundler&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install bundler
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clone Jacman theme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/Simpleyyt/jekyll-theme-next.git
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cd &lt;/span&gt;jekyll-theme-next
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install Jekyll and other dependencies from the GitHub Pages gem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run your Jekyll site locally:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-sh highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;exec &lt;/span&gt;jekyll server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Details：&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.github.com/articles/setting-up-your-github-pages-site-locally-with-jekyll/&quot;&gt;Setting up your GitHub Pages site locally with Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;multiple-languages-support-including-english--russian--french--german--simplified-chinese--traditional-chinese&quot;&gt;Multiple languages support, including: English / Russian / French / German / Simplified Chinese / Traditional Chinese.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Default language is English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-yml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;language&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;en&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# language: zh-Hans&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# language: fr-FR&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# language: zh-hk&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# language: zh-tw&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# language: ru&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# language: de&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;language&lt;/code&gt; field as following in site &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; to change to Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-yml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;language&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;zh-Hans&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comment-support&quot;&gt;Comment support.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NexT has native support for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DuoShuo&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;/code&gt; comment systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the following snippets to your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-yml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;duoshuo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;enable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;shortname&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;your-duoshuo-shortname&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OR&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-yml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;disqus_shortname&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;your-disqus-shortname&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;social-media&quot;&gt;Social Media&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NexT can automatically add links to your Social Media accounts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-yml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;social&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;your-github-url&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;your-twitter-url&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;Weibo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;your-weibo-url&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;DouBan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;your-douban-url&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;ZhiHu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;your-zhihu-url&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feed-link&quot;&gt;Feed link.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Show a feed link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rss&lt;/code&gt; field in theme’s &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt;, as the following value:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rss: false&lt;/code&gt; will totally disable feed link.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rss:  &lt;/code&gt; use sites’ feed link. This is the default option.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Follow the installation instruction in the plugin’s README. After the configuration is done for this plugin, the feed link is ready too.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rss: http://your-feed-url&lt;/code&gt; set specific feed link.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;up-to-5-code-highlight-themes-built-in&quot;&gt;Up to 5 code highlight themes built-in.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NexT uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chriskempson/tomorrow-theme&quot;&gt;Tomorrow Theme&lt;/a&gt; with 5 themes for you to choose from.
Next use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;normal&lt;/code&gt; by default. Have a preview about &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;normal&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;night&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://iissnan.com/nexus/next/tomorrow-normal.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tomorrow Normal Preview&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://iissnan.com/nexus/next/tomorrow-night.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tomorrow Night Preview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chriskempson/tomorrow-theme&quot;&gt;Tomorrow Theme&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;configuration&quot;&gt;Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NexT comes with few configurations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-yml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Menu configuration.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;menu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;home&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;archives&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;/archives&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Favicon&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;favicon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;/favicon.ico&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Avatar (put the image into next/source/images/)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# can be any image format supported by web browsers (JPEG,PNG,GIF,SVG,..)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;avatar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;/default_avatar.png&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Code highlight theme&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# available: normal | night | night eighties | night blue | night bright&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;highlight_theme&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;normal&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Fancybox for image gallery&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;fancybox&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Specify the date when the site was setup&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;since&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;2013&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;browser-support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://iissnan.com/nexus/next/browser-support.png&quot; alt=&quot;Browser support&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/next-tutorial</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/next-tutorial</guid>
        
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Neither a drug addict nor an alcoholic? Now it’s time to get rid of sugar</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We all know the danger of alcohol and frequently overuse of it can lead to several liver diseases. Anyone who hasn’t had any alcohol or doesn’t know it is toxic can easily tell its side effects, without knowing how it affects your body inside, after a few drinks of it. You will notice how your heart rate increases and losing the ability to control your car. Those are symptoms of being drunk, or intoxicated. The hangover next day will surely confirm it is toxic if you still have any doubt about it. The reason you can feel the alcohol is that a small amount of the alcohol is metabolized by your brain, while most of it is processed by the liver. This is also why you will develop a series of serious liver diseases if you consume alcohol every day. Like alcohol, all sorts of toxic substances are detoxified by the liver, frequent consumption leads to all kinds of health problems. But what if there is a toxin that leads you to the same situation without affecting your brain, would it be more dangerous to you? This substance is sugar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Sugar is a poison. It is a chronic, dose dependent hepato/liver toxin” — Dr. Robert Lustig&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we know alcohol is toxic, let’s first figure out how alcohol works in our bodies, and then compare it with how sugar works. Ethanol, which is called alcohol in everyday life, is not necessary for any biological processes, so it is primarily processed like a toxin in a liver. When we drink any alcoholic beverages, around 80% of ethanol will be processed by livers, making livers working four times harder than eating the same amount of meat because organs, like stomach, can’t handle it. Ethanol will be diffused into acetaldehyde in cells, leading to generating reactive oxygen species (ROS). ROS damages proteins and causes cancers. It is also one of the key factors of ageing. Acetaldehyde will then be converted into acetate which goes into mitochondria. Acetate in mitochondria will then goes into TCA cycle and be converted into citrates. Part of these citrates will finally become VLDL, which is called bad fat causing visceral fat. Some citrate will become free fatty acids in your muscles, making you have muscle insulin resistance. Some fat that could not get out of your liver will cause the fatty liver disease. Ethanol, ROS and part of the fat stimulate JNK-1, causing more pSer-IRS-1. With more and more pSer-IRS-1 in your body, your pancreas needs to work harder to generate more insulin out. How about sugar? Like Ethanol, fructose in sugar is not necessary to the body so that it will be almost 100% processed in the liver. Except for the part about ROS as mentioned above, sugar follows exactly the same processes in your body. The only difference for sugar is that you will suffer from non-alcoholic fatty liver disease instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beside the toxification, sugar is addictive. According to American Psychiatric Association, addiction, AKA substance dependence, is defined as if you would have three or more symptoms or not when your body is constantly consuming the substance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tolerance. Either you need to increase the amount of the substance to achieve intoxication or the desired effect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Withdrawal. Either the characteristic withdrawal syndrome or taking the same substance to relieve or avoid withdrawal symptoms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is often taken in larger amount or over a longer period than intended.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A persistent desire or unsuccessful efforts to cut down or control the use.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A lot of time spending in activities to obtain the substance, use the substance, or recover from its effects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Important social, occupational, or recreational activities are given up or reduced because of substance use.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is used continuously despite knowledge of having a persistent physical or psychological problem that is likely to have been caused or exacerbated by the substance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who try to quit sugar consistently report symptoms like lightheadedness, headaches, anxiety, mood swings, general fatigue, and physical tremors.So what’re the benefits if you quit eating sugar. here are some major improvements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better dental health. Sugar causes the bacteria in the mouth to flourish. excessive consumption of sugar increases the chances of tooth decay and other dental problems. Reduction of sugar intake promotes healthier teeth and gums.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better sleep. Excessive sugar consumption can not only cause a drop in your energy levels but can also cause sleep disruption. Reducing sugar intake helps to improve sleep quality and relief from insomnia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve digestive health. Reducing the sugar consumption will improve the ability of the digestive system to process foods. It also helps to avoid constipation and other problems associated with the colon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Healthier heart. According to the American Heart Association, reduction of sugar intake reduces the risk of suffering from a heart attack, because sugar poses many dangers to heart health.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Healthier skin. sometimes sugar causes acne and cracking of the skin. Some people have reported a clear skin after quitting sugar consumption in researches&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improve energy levels. Excess consumption of sugar hinders the body’s ability to keep its energy reserve as high as possible. Studies have proven that having too much sugar in the body can cause a crash in one’s daily activities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduce cancer risk. Studies have shown that sugar provides nutrients to cancer cells. Therefore reducing your sugar consumption may help prevent various types of cancer and the replication of malignant cells throughout the body.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stable weight. Sugary foods have a high amount of fats, calories and carbohydrates which are causes of weight gain. Reducing sugar intake will make it easier to achieve a healthy and balanced weight.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Protect the liver. Excessive glucose and fructose can lead to a toxic build-up in your liver. This is similar to what happens when you consume too much alcohol. Medical experts have recommended a liver detox to reduce the risk of developing liver problems that are caused by excessive sugar consumption.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Become happier. Excess sugar consumption can cause resistance to leptin, the hormone that is responsible for sending signals to your brain that you’re full.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you read carefully, you would notice the phrase “excess consumption”. You might accept the fact I listed above, but you would think your daily sugar intake is lower than your health recommendation. The truth is, you can still overdose even if you don’t use any sugar when you cook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if we literally quit sugar? Or will the problem be solved if we don’t eat anything called sugar? The answer is simply no. The problem we are facing right now is that we could be overdosed without even realising it. With growing awareness of the importance of diet, many people are trying to lower their fat and calorie intake in order to achieve greater health. At the same time, more and more companies are adding sugars to their products in order to maintain their physical and psychological attractiveness while still marketing them as healthy food. An estimated 80% or more of our food has unnecessary added sugars. The taste of food may become bland and weird when the fat has been removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies want to ensure their products appeal to customers to maximise their profit. Thus, food companies use extra sugars to compensate for any lose of taste or texture. Since sugar is on our blacklists, food companies won’t directly list it on the ingredient lists. High fructose corn syrup has rightfully gained a bad reputation. However, as well as items we might easily identify as sugar, such as: golden sugar, raw sugar, brown sugar, grape sugar etc.. We may not realise dehydrated cane juice, honey and rice syrup are also forms of sugar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are more than 50 names of sugars, and this is how the companies make us feel better while keeping the sugar in. In the film The Sugar Film, Damon Gameau planned diets with plenty of so-called healthy low-fat foods, like yoghurt, whole grain cereals and fruit juice. His goal was to eat foods marked as healthy while reaching the average sugar intake of a typical Australian. By swapping a part of food with sugar while maintaining the same calories everyday for a month, he gained 18 kg and nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. He also suffered from consistent fatigue and lethargy. This result perfectly demonstrated how bad it could be if you put your trust in those healthy but sugary foods. I strongly suggest everyone watching it. Taking a spoon of sugar or overdosing yourself a week won’t kill you, but a disease doesn’t happen with one meal, but it happens with a thousand. But that’s what we have because now sugar is with every meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more you learn, the more you’ll want to stop eating sugar. This is your rational thinking, but sugar seems a magic to lure you, and you can’t resist it. Let’s start fixing this with your brain. Sugar keeps you consuming it regardless of the amount of food you have eaten. The first reason of it is its biological addiction, which gives you a sense of pleasure by stimulating particular hormone when you eat it. When you constantly eat sugar, you create tolerance of it just as drug addicts have tolerance after taking drugs for a long time, which makes you crave more if you want to maintain the same level of happiness when you consume it. The second reason is sugar keep you feel hungry. Excessive intake of sugar leads to excessive insulin. When there is too much insulin in your body, your brain will stop receiving leptin signal, which makes your brain think you’re starving. Our body has built up a series of reactions to save energy when the food is scarce in the environment. If you continuously feel hungry, your brain will turn your body into a power saving mode, which makes you feel lethargy. We will also feel less happy when we’re trying to quit sugar, but we should persuade ourselves that it’s a fallacy and keep trying it for at least one or two weeks. By the end of it, I believe you will feel happier and more energetic. After tuning your brain, we also have to fight against the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are bombarded with colourful advertisements of food which contains vast amount to sugar. Instead of trying to resist from seeing, thinking, eating industrialised and deeply processed food, we could change our internal routines of eating food. If your routine is going to a supermarket, finding something that is pre-made and beautiful, taking off the package and eating food, the advertisements have a significant influence on you. But if you deconstruct the routine and change it to see real food, check freshness and nutritiousness, cook food and eat it, then you probably stop noticing anything from advertising and become much easier to resist sugary food. Furthermore, you could try to make the new routine as a habit. Our brain always tries its best to save energy, so it builds up tonnes of autopilot routines. Those are called habits by us. If we repetitively follow healthier eating procedures, it helps our brains reinforce the new program as a new habit to replace the older one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have researches about what is a healthy food. For any scientific supported health food, no matter it’s low carb, high carb, vegetarian, etc., they all lack deeply processed food. Traditional Chinese, Japanese, Mediterranean food are great, but the deeply processed food inside a package from them are as bad as others.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/neither-a-drug-addict-nor-an-alcoholic</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/neither-a-drug-addict-nor-an-alcoholic</guid>
        
        <category>Health</category>
        
        <category>Sugar</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
