<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>management on Engineering Field Notes</title>
    <link>https://kenmlai.me/tags/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in management on Engineering Field Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://kenmlai.me/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202003192005/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202003192005/</guid>
      <description>How long should you work a time A break is ~15 minutes. Before noon, 90 minutes a time before taking a break; After noon, take a break every hour.1
  Here’s exactly how long your work breaks should be  &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202003151302/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202003151302/</guid>
      <description>High-Intensity Circuit Training Using Body Weight HICT can be a fast and efficient way of lose weight and fat and an efficient approach to decreasing insulin resistance too.1
 8-12 repetitions are recommend by ACSM for each major muscle group of a bout1 people with hypertension or deart disease should avoid isometric exercises. 1 It may NOT good for training for absolute strength, specific endurance and other specific performance.1  Exercise Order</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202003151330/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202003151330/</guid>
      <description>How to find which process has occupied a specific port Methods netstat1 sudo apt install net-tools sudo netstat -ltnp  lsof1 sudo apt install lsof sudo lsof -i :80   DON&amp;rsquo;T forget the : before the port number  fuser1 sudo apt install psmisc # show a port number is listening by a process number sudo fuser 3306/tcp # check the process name by the process number ps -p [processID] -o comm=  Usability Test    Method Linux Mac     netstat ✅ ❌   lsof ✅ ✅   fuser ✅ ❌      Linux: Find Out Which Port Number a Process is Listening on  &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202003141522/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202003141522/</guid>
      <description>Meek使用前置域名，将Tor流量伪装成访问其他HTTPS站点的流量。1 基于云流量混淆的Tor匿名通信识别方法 &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/essays/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 19:51:25 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/essays/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>fdjakfjda;jk 附近的考拉范德萨看赖健；理发师简单快乐 fdsajkfldaklf</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202003061909/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202003061909/</guid>
      <description>Since AWS lambda bills according to the number of calls and computing time. We can use parallel process to reduce the time to save the cost1.
with concurrent.futures.ThreadPoolExecutor(max_workers=60)as executor: result = executor.map(core_function, iterable)    Halving our AWS Lambda bill with parallel processing in Python  &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002190000/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002190000/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Ansible: Setup, Configure, and Ad Hoc Commands Deep Dive&amp;rdquo; study note The course focuses on ad hoc commands of Ansible
about Ansible ansible is run a task against a single host ansible-playbook is running a set of tasks against a single or a groups of hosts
##how to setup ansible default inventory file: /etc/ansible/hosts
it&amp;rsquo;s recommended to add a new user for ansible. Besides security considerations, systems may not share the same user name in default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002191731/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002191731/</guid>
      <description>所谓的“1万小时学习”，更多的是强调学习方法。在不正确或者低效率的方法下，收益可能远不如话费的时间价值大。 这种学习方法包括： 永远只在“学习区</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002182245/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002182245/</guid>
      <description>confirmation bias （确认偏误） 是一种心理认知倾向：人们倾向于主动寻找自己相信的信息，即使有相反的信息，也可能会被用来加强已有的观念。1 主动获取和自己观点相</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002122152/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002122152/</guid>
      <description>minimal path to success providing short-term rewards and then continuously help to customers is the minimal path to awesome1.
  &amp;ldquo;PEOPLE NEED MY PRODUCT!&amp;rdquo; (BUT DO THEY WANT IT?) &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002101022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002101022/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s zombie startups? companies that have the outside appearance of a startup but that aren’t moving that quickly and that are likely to always stay small, kept alive with suboptimal sources of funding (bad angel investors, subsidies, grants, etc.)1
  [[Avoiding Zombie Startups - Welcome to The Family]] &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002081057/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002081057/</guid>
      <description>Unfamiliarity impedes adoption of productions. A product should be improved and innovated with a similarity of existence, which makes users easier to understand and expect1.
  [[California Roll Rule: The Familiar Done Differently | NirandFar]] &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002071114/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002071114/</guid>
      <description>OSPF study notes Packet type:
 Hello: discover and maintain neighbornood DBD: LSA header information, like a dictionary of LSAs LSR: request LSA LSU: update LSA (may contain several LSA) LS ACK: confirmation  LSA type:
   Type advertizer scope content      1 all routers running ospf local area directly connected interfaces    2 DR local area mask of a MA network    3 ABR AS summary of LSA 1 &amp;amp; 2    4 ABR in which area an ASBR exist AS where the ASBR is    5 ASBR AS external routes    6   Group Membership LSA    7 ASBR of NSSA in the NSSA external routes    8 all routers in IPv6 (LSA 1 for ipv6)      9 DR in IPv6 (LSA 2 for ipv6)      10   MPLS TE    11   MPLS TE     Route types:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002071240/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002071240/</guid>
      <description>STP study notes used to prevent loop in L2 by selecting root bridge to make a tree-like logical topology
Election:
 Priority. smaller is better MAC. smaller is better  steps of Blocking a interface:
 all ports of the root bridge are designated interfaces, in forwarding state select all root port on non-root bridges, in forwarding state select designated interfaces in the rest networks, priority -&amp;gt; cost -&amp;gt; mac (smaller is better) block the rest interfaces  root port selection rule:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002072032/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002072032/</guid>
      <description>Partnership Fallacy a simply combination of people/firms/teams with different strength &amp;amp; weakness doesn’t necessary mean a better team, ideas are biased based on their strength and often lack wholistic view1.
  [[Bill Barnett on Strategy: The Partnership Fallacy]] &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002072230/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002072230/</guid>
      <description>why customers pay Customers pay for what they have faced in lives, not average people need to do.1
Focusing on what users need is more directly than what developers want1 2.
  [[Jobs to be Done - Christensen Institute : Christensen Institute]] &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
 [[Marc Benioff: Win Customers by Treating Them Like Partners - Salesforce Blog]] &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002061447/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002061447/</guid>
      <description>ratio between lines written and in production The ratio lines of codes, words of books and etc. is 10:1 between lines ever written and lines in final production.1
  [[The 10:1 rule of writing and programming]] &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002061500/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002061500/</guid>
      <description>Pros &amp;amp; Cons of using microservices Pros: Easier to test, deploy, and monitor since each service works independently,
 service can scale better at a specific bottleneck can serving older and newer version at the same time, and let older ones phase out gradually development, test &amp;amp; deployment of each service is independent  Cons: latency between services and management issue
 A service depending on several calls to others may suffer from a huge delay different teams may work on the same/similar service at the same time, extra assessments are needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002061611/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002061611/</guid>
      <description>Meeting
Meetings with purposes are good, otherwise they are finding problems with solutions.1
informal chat is also a meeting, that is useful
  [[Bill Barnett on Strategy: Delete All Meetings!]] &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002062323/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenmlai.me/notes/202002062323/</guid>
      <description>HSRP study notes Active, Standby routers:
 Active: the router forwards packets in a HSRP group Standby: the router listens in a HSRP group  Hello packet send 224.0.0.2
election rule: priority (default is 100) &amp;gt; interface ip (bigger is better)
State machine:
 Initial Learn Listen Speak Standby Active  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
