<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IGMP on Engineering Field Notes</title>
    <link>https://kenlai.me/tags/IGMP/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IGMP on Engineering Field Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kenlai.me/tags/IGMP/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scenarios of IGMP Snooping Multicast Forwarding</title>
      <link>https://kenlai.me/post/Scenarios-of-IGMP-Snooping-Multicast-Forwarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenlai.me/post/Scenarios-of-IGMP-Snooping-Multicast-Forwarding/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve discussed what is IGMP snooping and its forwarding rules for different packets in my last post. I just want to give some typical scenarios in IGMP snooping for your better understanding.
Scenario 1: Switch forwarding multicast traffic to a multicast router and hosts In the topology shown above, the switch acting as a pure L2 device interconnects multicast router, which directly connects to the Source A for multicast group 239.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is IGMP Snooping</title>
      <link>https://kenlai.me/post/What-is-IGMP-Snooping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kenlai.me/post/What-is-IGMP-Snooping/</guid>
      <description>What does IGMP Snooping Do IGMP snooping is used to monitor the traffic of IGMP protocol between hosts and multicast-enabled routers. The switch uses it to learn which interface has an interested receiver and forward multicast traffic only to these interfaces. This feature could save bandwidth by allowing it to send traffic only needed, rather than flooding all multicast packets to all interfaces.
IGMP Snooping and Forwarding Interfaces To determine how to forward multicast traffic, IGMP snooping maintains a “table” about the interfaces information:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>